Okay, this is I usually use this for my
soil when I'm potting up or I used to.
Um, but I want to try something
different with it down here. Uh, this is
where I grow my seeds. It's where my
worms are. Um, so hopefully later this
week we can get to that. Um, but it's
cold outside again. Winter has returned
uh for at least a few days. Um, and I'm
supposed to be spending my week down
here catching up on my seating. So, I
thought I'd take you down here, show you
where I'm at, what things are looking
like. It's not all going well. Some is.
Um, but uh, yeah, I do have a few
mistakes already this year. Okay, so
first up, I thought we would look at the
cutings I did a couple weeks ago and um,
to be honest, I'm kind of bummed uh,
with how they're looking. And this is
totally my fault. Um,
I put the lid on, I put them under
lights, the same thing I did to the
round before, and like the first batch I
did, um, they look great. They're all
potted up. Um, they just rooted after a
few weeks. So, success. So, I didn't
really think much of it. I put this um
batch with the lid on under the lights,
but I put it on a different shelf and
this it was right against the lights. I
think with the amount of moisture in
there and then the heat from the lights,
it was just too much. So, yeah, a lot of
them kind of show like a fungus. Uh the
the leaves are turning brown. Um they're
dying. Some full out just died and
rotted. Um, but yeah, so once I realized
that was happening, I moved it to this
set of lights. Um, I opened up the
vents, gave it a little bit more
airflow. Um, and it's not a total loss.
Like I think some of them Oh, like Yeah,
look at this. Um, we have roots. So,
it's not like I definitely have some, so
it's fine. And the chrysanthemums at
this end, uh, yeah, they're showing
roots, too. I think chrysanthemums just
root a lot quicker and probably can
tolerate worse conditions. So, maybe
I'll just get this out of here and pot
up what I can. And um Oh, yeah. Look at
more roots.
Anyways, lesson learned. Uh you have to
uh keep an eye not too wet, uh not too
dry, not too close to the lights.
So, I don't actually have a lot seated.
I think other years I might have a bit
more seated, but I'm trying to uh not be
over agressive with seating too early
on. Um, so this side here is my cutings.
At the top is the perennial scabiosa
that I seeded a month ago. Um, it is
looking great. So, super happy with
that. And then I have my eucalyptus
babies um on this shelf, too. I do find
um they they look okay. They are I find
I have difficulty when they're so little
um either overwatering them or
underwatering them or giving them too
much fertilizer. And I always lose some
to like I'm not exactly sure their
leaves kind of shrivel up and um yeah,
it doesn't always mean that they're
going to die, but they at this stage I
feel like it's a delicate uh time. So
they look okay. I think they look okay.
Uh hopefully in the next few weeks they
really take off and we're past this
sensitive stage.
Okay, so most of what's in the basement
right now is lizanthis. Um I have my
first three rounds seated. So, I started
with my orange trays uh mid January. Um
then I did all my green trays. Um I
filled up my pink trays for my third
round. And this week I need to do my
fourth round. So, um yeah, I think it's
looking pretty good. Pretty happy with
the growth um for the first few um
considering when you see a fresh tray
that's just uh uncovered how tiny they
are and then I come and look at my
orange trays and I think, "Oh, yes, we
have growth." So, not all of them have
germinated great. I'm trying to use up
all my old seed and I had some seed that
was um four years old. Yeah. So that did
not germinate well, but for most things
I have fairly good germination rates.
Yeah. And so this is the first year that
I um seeded my lizanths by putting them
into the soil blocks before I pushed the
soil blocks out. And um my goal was to
not have to break off any of the pellets
after they germinated or I know a lot of
people spray their trays down and I've
never liked spraying. I get a lot more
algae and I just find it very time
consuming. So I'm not a mister with a
spray bottle on my seedlings. Um but I
have to say that I'm very happy. There's
very few Yeah. that look like this where
I still have to break the pallet. Like I
think that's the um Yeah. I just I just
don't have to do that this year where
other years I was breaking off a lot
more pellets uh after germination.
Okay, so the worms and me are feeling a
little squished.
Um, I I I don't know. I keep a container
by my kitchen. I fill it up with food
scraps and stuff that I know that the
worms will eat. And I I have quite a
bit. I feel like more food than I have
room to feed. And I can always use more
castings. So, I don't think I want
another worm tower cuz I I actually
think um I want to try this. I think
this might be easier to feed into and
it's just more space. Um, so what I'm
going to try and do with this blue bin
is make a wedge system uh worm farm
here. So I'll still have the two towers.
Um, but I can give them a little bit
more time to process the food without
jamming more in there. And then I'll
also have uh this uh little farm here.
So the idea with a wedge system is that
you put your uh worm castings, more
finished uh compost at one end. So this
is where I dumped the tray from my
tower. So, there's worms in here. Um,
and there's lots for them to still
finish. And then you cover that with
bedding. So, I am using leaves and I
have cardboard and other stuff to put
in. And then it's kind of uh the next
wedge in the system. And then I will
feed into the bedding area. Um, and the
next time I will put in some more
bedding and feed into there. And
everything from this far end will slowly
finish and the worms will like the idea
is that they'll move across and keep
eating their way down. So, I think it'll
be easier for me to quickly feed in
here. That's the idea. And then also
easier for me to find some finished uh
worm castings that that end without
having to pull apart my whole tower. So,
I don't mind my towers. I just I just
want to try something new and I just
need more space for worms so I can grow
more worms and ideally get more
castings. Okay, I found this like
thicker sheet of plastic down here in
the basement. I'm going to use that as
my lid because I don't want to dry out.
So, if there's nothing on top with the
dry air in the house right now, um I
want to prevent that. And then I also
like my makeshift uh place here. Um I
put some wood down to stop it from
rolling just in case. Um and it's
slightly sloped. So if it's too wet, cuz
I do tend to feed uh a lot of stuff that
has a lot of water in it. Um that will
drain to this end. So I can keep an eye
on if it's too dry or too wet. If it
ends up being too dry, I can always add
more moisture. But I don't The problem
with making videos is that um I think if
I didn't, my family probably wouldn't
realize what I'm doing down here. Um but
now they're might see that I've put a
barrel of worms.
And I don't know what they're going to
think, but I think this is super cool.
And I'm crossing my fingers that I have
success with this.
So when I see the tray, it usually comes
on this shelf at this side of the room.
So uh these blue trays are this week's
round of lizanths. So I'm working on the
blue. I'm not quite done. So this last
pink was from two weeks ago and the rest
of them have all moved over there. But
this one I'm waiting a little bit longer
on. I think it's the last one I did. Um
these shorter trays I'm using just for
the random stuff. So, I have um so far
Crespedia,
uh uh FeverFW, Dianthis, and a few snapd
dragons. So, I'm going to hopefully do
more of that uh this weekend and next
week, and some of the other cool annuals
or perennials. I got to dig through my
seed box and see what I have. And down
here, I have some space to get some more
trays in this weekend. Um the bottom are
the delinium that I took out of the
fridge. Uh, so I put them in the fridge,
I don't know, mid January, and I'm super
excited about all of them that have
popped up now. Uh, yeah, they're looking
great. So, that's super cool cuz
delphinium has become a new favorite
thing for me to grow. And then this is
the uh
the first few tubers uh dia tubers I
potted up. And yeah, I think I'm going
to have to start taking uh cutings soon.
So, we'll see if these uh if I have any
luck with these cutings this year. Okay,
so um I just counted. I think I have
room for 38 more trees down here. Uh
which is super. That should keep me busy
for the next uh couple weeks. And then
um yeah, I think we're only like maybe
less than 20 days until spring, but some
of this stuff can start transitioning to
the garage and then yeah, in a month
possibly out uh to the wagon outside.
So, um yeah, I think it looks good. Uh
even though there's like less uh trays
than I normally have for February, I'm
I'm happy with where I'm at and I'm
trying to be very intentional with what
I'm seating this year so I don't grow
things that maybe I don't need to or um
that I won't possibly sell. So, and I
haven't I haven't let a tray dry out
yet. Usually, at some point, I kill a
tray or two by not watering. Um Oh, but
actually I'm looking at this tray. It's
not dried out. But this is one mistake.
This was the very first mistake I made
this year is that um it's eucalyptus and
I seated it. I put the uh the label in
and then I realized there was um already
a label in the tray. So I had grabbed a
tray that I thought was empty and I
double seated it with two varieties
different varieties of eucalyptus. So
it's a little bit crowded. They look
okay. I'll just make sure I give them
extra space uh in the field this spring.
So yeah, that's uh my seating room for
the end of February. Uh thank you for
coming on my little tour down here. And
uh thank you for watching and
subscribing and liking and becoming
members, all of that. I really
appreciate it. And I'll see you again
next time.