We're in Soul trying supposedly the best
donuts in Korea. Let's start with the
meat one. I'm going to save till last
cuz I'm not sure about that one. But
this one is like chocolate caramel
crunch.
Very, very crunchy. This one is the
white chocolate lemon.
It's definitely very lemony, but I don't
taste any white chocolate. I just taste
a lot of lemon. This one was just called
cacao. That's all it said.
Just a normal doughnut. Thought there
was something inside of this one. Butter
and condensed milk.
I like felt my heart heart start to
palpitate there. So far, that one was my
favorite. Like that butter is just so
cream and smooth and it just goes down
really easy. Usually I'm not a huge fan
of eating blocks of butter,
surprisingly, but yeah, this one's the
pistachio filled one.
Oh wow.
Oh wow. This one's like refreshing.
After all those like super like sweet
ones, this one's really refreshing and
it's filled. Man, I don't know how I
feel about this. Pushcido and maple like
meat on a donut. Dude, I'm not really
like that type of guy. Usually if I eat
meat, I just like eating straight meat.
Oh, that. That was the most
expensive one. Probably because of the
pushcido. But I don't ever want to eat
that again. And I don't ever want to see
that again. Save it for your trip to
Korea.