Welcome back to another video, guys.
Today we are learning English in the
Rocky Mountains.
>> It's brisk out here. Very sticky. A
moose.
>> Their coffee gets sold in Alberta.
>> We are at Radium Hot Springs to make
kindling for the fire. It's the highest
town in Canada.
>> Start the word count and let's go.
>> So, what is this place famous for?
>> They're famous for their coffee. They
are a Canadian roastery and this is
their location in British Columbia.
>> Are they all over Canada?
>> Uh their coffee gets sold in Alberta and
I'm presuming all over all over the
place. And seeing that we are coffee
lovers. Uh it's a nice treat for us to
come. I'll have a cappuccino, please.
And then is the Canadiano just black
coffee or
>> it's an American.
>> Okay. Yep. Okay. I'll have one of those.
>> And are they just there to go?
>> It's it's to go. We'll have it to go.
Yeah, we'll just take it to go.
>> 8 12 or 16.
>> Um
12. I'll take the 12 for that one.
>> Perfect.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
Is that your cappuccino?
We have a cafeteria for Maria.
>> Yes. Thank you so much. Here you can
have a look at it.
>> It's really good. Cheers.
>> Okay. How's your coffee?
>> It's delicious. It is kicking horse
coffee, but it actually says kickass.
>> And how's your one?
>> It's uh Canadian.
>> Canadian.
>> Okay. So we got kicking horse coffee.
This is a very popular coffee in Canada
and it was founded in 1996 here in
Invamir BC. And uh it's one of the best
places to work in Canada. And how is
your coffee? That's a strong coffee or
what?
>> It's strong. That's why only I can only
drink a normal cup. I can't drink a
bucket like some people do. So this is a
8 oz in.
>> Yeah. That was just a quick quick uh pit
stop here in Inir kicking horse to get
some coffee. I don't drink coffee
personally, so uh I didn't get any.
>> Oh, and did you show?
>> My mom and dad did.
>> Yeah, we bought some coffee, too, for
the road.
>> Are those coffee beans or coffee
grounds?
>> These are coffee grounds cuz I don't
have my mill, my coffee mill with me.
Oh,
>> okay. But now we're back at the camper
van. So,
>> let's go.
>> Let's go.
It's brisk out here.
Let's go to the lake.
>> Let's go.
>> There is a lot of wind today. I only see
one person out on the lake kayaking.
This reminds me of the homes along the
BC coast like especially in all those
like uh small islands and stuff. All
those houses.
>> Yes.
>> And this this beach is very rocky. This
is a very rocky beach. See all those
pebbles? Like a small rock like this.
This is called a pebble. A small rock
like this is called a pebble. But yeah,
this water is uh water is pretty choppy.
The water is pretty choppy. If the water
was smoother and calmer, I would be able
to skip this. But it's pretty choppy
right now. So, I don't think I could
skip it. No.
>> Look, it's all rocks in there, too.
>> Yeah. And you can see this you can see
this foam.
All this foam along along the shoreline.
What is the What is this foam? I just
asked Chachi BT. So, we'll see uh what
this foam is along the shoreline.
>> Natural lake. Okay. So, the foam you see
along the shoreline is natural lake foam
forms when organic material in the water
like decomposed plants, algae, and other
natural matter breaks down and releases
compounds called surfactants. These
surfactants lower the surface tension of
the water. So, when the waves and wind
stir the lake, bubbles form and gather
into foam. So, it's harmless. It's
caused by the wind and the waves making
it build up and it sticks to where the
water meets the land. So, it's just
formed by the lake. It's nothing nothing
bad. You could probably eat it, but I
would not recommend that.
It's pretty cold. Let's head back.
I don't know what happened to all the
nice weather.
>> Yesterday was beautiful.
Today,
>> is it always like this here?
>> No. The last time we were here in the
summer, it was the lake was calm. We had
ice cream here. It was beautiful.
>> Let's go.
>> English opens doors to jobs,
friendships, travel, and more. But the
hardest part is finding someone to
practice with every single day. That's
where Easy Speak AI helps. Real speaking
practice anytime, anywhere. With 12 plus
AI tutors, you choose the vibe.
Friendly, professional, or casual.
Lessons are practical. They focus on
real life skills like travel, health
conversations, and real life chats you
actually use. Oh, I think I'm seasick. I
do not feel good. Let's call Ava. Hey,
Ava. I really don't feel good. I think I
have seasickness. So, I want you to help
me practice for when I go to the
pharmacy.
>> What exactly are you feeling right now?
>> Right now, I'm just feeling very
nauseous. My head is pounding. I feel
dizzy.
>> Are you also feeling clammy or perhaps a
bit weak?
>> I do feel quite weak actually.
>> Do you have any other symptoms like a
cough or sore throat?
>> No, I don't have a sore throat and uh I
don't have a cough either.
>> That's good news. Are you experiencing
any chills or feeling particularly
tired? Almost like you could just sleep
all day. I am not feeling chills, but I
am feeling very tired.
>> They might also ask about how long
you've had these symptoms and if
anything makes them better or worse.
>> This feels like a real conversation. The
tutor responds naturally, corrects you
fast, and builds confidence every
session. Everything is personalized. Set
your goals and interests, and the app
adapts everything for you. The review
tab shows exactly how you're improving.
5 minutes a day is all it takes. Imagine
where your English can be in 3 months.
More confidence, smoother conversations,
and no hesitation when it really
matters. If you're ready to speak with
confidence, download Easy Speak AI using
the link in my description or pinned
comment. Practice for 7 days straight
and one of you will be entered to win a
free 1-year plan of Easy Speak AI. Thank
you Easy Speak AI for sponsoring today's
video.
>> Okay, we're headed through the
underpass.
to the hot springs. Okay, so we are at
Radium Hot Springs that started in 1914
here. And the hotring is actually
located right there.
So that's just where the pool is, but
the source of the hotring is in these
mountains right here nearby. And they
just bring the warm water and fill up
this pool. So this is the hotring, and
it's a pretty popular one. Half of it is
closed right now for renovation, but
this half is open. That water doesn't
even look that warm, though. I don't see
any steam coming out. And it's pretty
cold out here. So So that's an empty
pool.
You see the pool's empty. And that slide
slides into the pool, but I guess
they're cleaning it. Yeah, there's a
diving board right there. And they're
cleaning the pool, so there's no water
in the pool. Hopefully they have that up
and running soon. So these are all the
national parks in Canada.
So there's a lot in this area right
here. And this is where we are right
now. This is like the Rocky Mountains on
the border between Alberta and British
Columbia.
And you have a lot up here in the north
in the territories.
>> Pretty sure this is the biggest national
park in North America.
>> It looks big.
>> It's called Aabaska National Park or
something.
>> Okay. So, this is an underpass. You can
see here the highway goes on top and we
walk under it. So, it's an underpass for
pedestrians. And these right here are
paw prints from different animals.
There's a wolverine paw print, a cougar,
pear, coyote,
deer, and wolf. And then on this side,
this is a coyote.
This is a wolf.
This is a cougar, a deer, and a moose.
Yeah. And this right here is the This is
like an overpass. So animals cross here.
So instead of crossing over the
highways, they just cross over right
here.
>> Animal crossover.
>> Animal crossing. There you go. There you
go.
>> So animal crossing.
>> Thank you.
>> So I guess that's that was actually
pretty obvious. Animal crossing. Okay.
So technically this is called a wildlife
crossing and it's just for animals to
cross the highway without getting in the
way of vehicles and getting hit.
So, we've just arrived at our campsite
in B National Park. Dude, that is a nice
mountain. So, that is our view today.
Look at that. And then this is the
campsite we're in. So, you're making a
tepee fire.
He's using the the hand torch to start
the fire. Okay. So, now my dad is
chopping wood with a hatchet to make
kindling for the fire.
Okay, so this is a hatchet because this
is small. An axe is similar to this but
a lot longer.
But a short one like this that's used
just for precision cutting and making
kindling is called a hatchet.
But now the fire is really going.
Okay guys, I'm going to make s'mores. I
have my marshmallows here.
and my chocolate cookie here. The fire
is kind of like way too big to make us
more, but I think if I hold it right
here,
>> marshmallow stick,
>> I'll be able to make a good one.
>> Okay, now let's put the my marshmallows
on my marshmallow roasting stick or my
marshmallow stick.
One. Let's cook these up.
So, now it's time to create my s'more
with four marshmallows
because that's the minimum.
I've got my s'more here.
The rule is always
one cracker and four marshmallows.
That way, the chocolate melts.
It's very
sticky.
The marshmallow is very sticky.
Okay, we're uh we're walking to the bus
stop right here to catch a bus into town
because we don't really want to drive
our camper van into town.
>> Isn't that right, Mom?
>> Yes, we're going to take the bus in.
It's $2 to come back and free to go, I
guess. So, Oh, really?
>> Yeah.
>> Free to go. I mean,
>> uh she told me that. Oh, she said.
>> Yeah. So, $2 to come back and we're on
route two. So, it goes to the Bam
Springs Hotel.
>> So, we should get off like
Moose Muskrat North and then then this
is the beginning of town. You can walk
through town
>> stuff cuz that's we get off here and
then this is the whole town. Check your
map again. What time
>> the bus comes? 6:06. I thought
>> I won't be spot on.
>> It's in 10 minutes. So, we have to wait
about 11 minutes. So, let's wait.
Bus is coming now.
>> I guess you put skier and stuff.
>> It's a Fairmont Hotel. Can we get into
the front? I
>> guess so.
>> Guess so.
>> Hi.
>> Hello. How are you?
>> Way down. You pay the way back.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> Okay, we're on the bus now.
>> $2 is not not too bad.
>> Well, on the way back, $2 for the total
of the trip pretty much. or if you're
only going one way, you'd be free. This
is a public transportation bus. It's
very clean.
Bamp was established as Canada's first
national park in 1885 and the world's
third national park in the whole world.
It was number three.
So Canada Goose is one of like the most
popular Canadian brands and at one point
it was known as the Gucci of winter and
they're actually a publicly traded
company on the Toronto and the New York
Stock Exchange. And these jackets are
very expensive. Like the average price
of these jackets $1,000, which is very
expensive for a winter jacket, but I
guess that's why people like it so much.
So, BA National Park was created after
Canadian Pacific Railroad workers found
a natural hotring here on Sulfur Mount
and then it was established as a
national park in Canada.
>> So, it's been a national park for h for
a long time.
>> And BA, the town we're in right now, is
one of the only towns that are actually
located inside a national park. So, BA
is one, Jasper's one. So, Alberta has
two
>> two towns located in a national park.
>> Yeah,
>> that's kind of cool.
>> It is. Four million people per year
travel to BA,
>> which is a lot.
>> I would believe that. And we're on the
off season now, so and it's still very
>> right now. It's not too busy, but it's
super busy because the summer it's
beautiful for hiking trails. There's
about 1,600 km of hiking trails or 1,000
mi in the summer. So, there's so much to
do. And in the winter there's
snowboarding, skiing. There's like three
ski hills just within the VA area. So,
there's a lot to do.
Did you know? Did you know Marine Lake
was once featured on the $20 bill?
>> No. It
>> used to be on the $20 bill.
>> Did Did you know we're going to go there
tomorrow?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I didn't actually know that.
>> And they used to call it the $20 view,
>> but I guess they changed it. I don't
even know who is on the $20 bill
anymore.
>> Wow.
>> Pretty cool.
>> I'm very warm cuz I wore long pants, but
Leon, you can see he just wore shorts,
so I'm sure he's pretty cold.
>> No, he's real Canadian.
Okay. So, this is the bridge or this is
the bridge. That is the river. This is
the Bow River. The same one through
Calgary.
>> Yep.
>> The same one that runs through Calgary.
It's the Bow River.
>> This is a nice river. It's very wide.
>> Looks very wide. And it looks very
shallow, too. Like, I could see the
bottom right here. I wonder why there's
a bunch of safety pylons on the right
hand side of this sidewalk. Should they
close the road off during the day? Look.
>> So, this is the fun fact. This is the
highest town in Canada. It sits at for
almost 1,400 m above sea level. So,
it's the highest town in Canada. And I
imagine there's a lot of high people
here as well since it's very close to
BC. If you know, you know.
>> If you know, you know. Yeah.
>> Caution. Sasquatch crossing.
So this is a this is a souvenir shop
we're in right now and they just sell
all these little things are called
souvenirs. So here are some magnet
souvenirs.
License plates, mugs,
chocolates,
maple syrup that's very popular in
Canada.
A lot of souvenirs here.
>> Moose.
>> A moose.
>> Moose
bear.
Oh yeah,
>> a proper one.
>> This is This is the moose with horns.
>> Or not horns, with antlers.
>> Yeah.
>> What you waiting for?
>> The bus.
>> Okay, so now we are back.
>> We're back at our campsite. Home.
>> Back at our campsite.
>> Home for the night.
>> We're back at our campsite now. We were
just in town.
We We got to see the town. Very nice
town, actually. here. I
>> think it's one of the nicest towns in
the mountains here in Canada.
>> But now we're heading back to our
campsite.
>> Hopefully there's no like bear that eats
us. If there is, hopefully they it eats
Leon first, honestly.
>> Well, they'll be full after they snack
on this one.
>> If you guys want to become more
confident and sound more natural when
you speak English, check out my Patreon.
I post videos there made exclusively
just to practice your English
pronunciation, your confidence, and your
fluency. So, if you guys want to sound
fluent in English and become more
confident, check out my Patreon in the
description.
>> Yeah, it was nice. Nice. The bus is very
convenient.
>> That's probably it for tonight. We're
just going to relax by this fire now.
>> And remember guys, you will become
fluent in English. Their coffee gets
sold in Alberta. It's my cappuccino.
>> It's brisk out here. See all those
pebbles? Like a small rock like this.
The water is pretty choppy. All this
foam along along the shoreline. The
source of the hotring is in these
mountains right here. Half of it is
closed right now for renovation, but
this half is open. So that's an empty
pool. And these right here are paw
prints from different animals. Hair,
coyote. This is like an overpass. So,
animals cross here
>> to make kindling for the fire. Okay,
guys. I'm going to make s'mores. Now,
let's put the my marshmallows on my
marshmallow roasting stick. It's very
sticky,
>> but it won't be spot on.
>> It's in 10 minutes. National Park in
1885. 1,600 km of hiking trails. The $20
bill.
>> No,
>> it used to be on the $20 bill. You can
see he just wore shorts, so I'm sure
he's pretty cold. This is the highest
town in Canada. A moose.