Welcome back to a new video, guys. As
you can see, there's nothing in my
freezer and almost nothing in my fridge.
That means we need to go do some
shopping at the grocery store. Join me.
Our list citrus. When's the last place
at any cooked fish here? Bar called
packaged goods from many liquid
compostables. Tour open stocking up.
Taste of start the word count and let's
go. Okay guys, we're at the market.
Seafood, poultry, meat, vegetables,
flowers, and spices. Let's go.
>> Doesn't look that big, but it looks kind
of nice.
>> This one isn't that big. This is the
ger. The ger isn't that big.
>> You want a basket?
>> Let's get a cart.
>> It was cold in there.
>> Yeah, I know. It feels full. Let's just
take a shopping cart.
>> You want that much stuff?
>> No, but we'll just grab a shopping cart.
Okay, so we're getting a shopping cart.
We don't really need that much stuff,
but uh might as well.
>> Yeah. I mean, no.
>> Oh, but it's cold in here.
>> Oh.
>> Oh, man. It's actually pretty small.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, let me pull out the list.
Okay. So, this is our list. Toilet
paper, bags, toothpaste, soap,
detergent, and large water bottles.
>> We have bags, though.
>> Do we?
>> I have that roll that we bought in South
Korea.
>> Oh, that's true. So, no bags. So, we do
not need bags anymore. Toilet paper,
toothpaste, soap, detergent, water
bottles, and uh soda. Look at all these
different roots here.
>> This looks like a melon, doesn't it? But
it's not.
>> Yeah. That's a sweet sour pomelo.
>> This is the biggest citrus fruit you can
buy.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. It's like a giant orange.
>> Wow. Citrus fruit.
>> And the skin on this is like an inch
thick.
>> Really? But you're paying for kilograms
here.
>> Exactly.
>> So you're kind of paying for skin
>> pretty much. But you can use the skin
too to make like candy and stuff if you
want.
>> Yeah. So this is like the produce
section. There are more fruits here.
There are bananas. You want to get some
bananas?
>> Yeah, we can get some bananas.
>> Well, let's grab some bananas then.
When's the last time you even had any
bananas?
>> Uh, yesterday.
>> Really?
>> A banana candy.
>> So, I just grabbed this uh bag. Now,
we're going to pick some bananas. Which
ones look good?
>> Maybe this one right here.
>> This one?
>> Yeah.
>> Now, I'm going to put the bananas in the
bag.
Bananas are now in the bag. And I'm
going to place it into my shopping cart.
If you want to get my 3,000 most common
English words PDF to help you understand
up to 95% of spoken English with real
clear definitions and examples organized
by suffer level and topic, then check
out the link in my description to get
it. What were you saying?
>> I was going to say that this one does
not look that good cuz it has
>> Yeah, it's starting to uh ripen too
much. If it ripens too much, it becomes
like brown and then black. Dude, I've
never seen a lot of these fruits.
>> This is a citrus, I think. Yeah. Look,
this is also a pomelo.
>> Oh, dude, that's huge.
>> They get really massive. But you got to
remember the skin is thick.
>> Yeah. And this is the vegetable area.
So, there are a lot of vegetables here.
>> Are you planning to do much cooking?
>> No. That's why I just bought bananas and
the rest of the stuff on my list. The
rest of the stuff, toilet paper,
toothpaste, soap, none of these are
ingredients for cooking. So, I won't be
doing any cooking, but let's add banana
to the list.
>> You know, we're in a Chinese grocery
when you have gluten balls.
>> And dude, look at those. Look at the
size of those peppers.
>> But I can guarantee that those are not
very spicy.
>> Okay, let's get the toilet paper
toothpaste. We have to go outside of the
produce area. Here is the fish area.
There are a bunch of fish here.
>> This almost looks like a piranha.
>> Like a piranha. Yeah, those look like
kind of like
>> those are mac.
>> Yeah. Let's go around this area. There
is just a lot more produce. And right
now I'm pushing the shopping cart
through the grocery store. And I guess
this is where you pay. Or no, that's
where you weigh your goods.
>> Oh, maybe you got to weigh there.
>> Yeah. Do you want to go weigh these
bananas?
>> Yeah, I'll weigh them.
>> I'll go to the side here. So yeah, Leon
is just weighing the banana.
>> What'd he say?
>> He's pointing me that way.
>> Okay, so that is a fruit weighing
station. So Leon needs to first go and
weigh his fruit. Usually in Canada they
do this when you get to the cash
register, but here it looks like they do
it here.
>> Thank you, bro. 420.
>> That's like uh A150
>> Canadian. So they weigh our bananas at
the fruit weighing station and then put
a price tag on it. So when we go to
check out, they'll scan this barcode.
And I guess that one was the vegetable
area.
>> Yeah, I think they the signs say
vegetable, too. Here we have some uh
frozen meats. Looks like Yeah. Beef
feet. Oh, they have Brazilian beef. Let
me know if you're from Brazil. Over here
they have mutton. Do you think we should
buy like condiments like ketchup or
barbecue sauce or something?
>> Yeah, I think ketchup would be good.
>> I think so. Oh, eggs. You think we
should buy some eggs?
>> Yeah, they're not bad. 11 per packet. 11
is what?
>> 11 is like $4.
>> Yeah.
>> Should we buy?
>> Yeah, these ones look popular. We'll
just get these ones. Yeah, I guess we
could go with that one. So, how many are
these?
>> Two dozen. Oh, 30.
>> 30 eggs. Now, I'm going to take the
carton of eggs and place it into the
shopping cart. I've just placed the eggs
into the shopping cart. Here we have
packaged goods. A lot of packaged goods.
I think we've added more things that
aren't from our list than from our
actual list. Toothpaste, soap,
detergent, toilet paper, water, and
soda. Oh, water is over here. Should we
just buy a big water and then we could
refill it at the Or should we buy like
something like this? No,
>> let's just take a big one.
>> Or actually, I think this would be a
better deal.
>> You have to get natural mineral water.
That's what you want to look for.
>> It's the same brand, Desel.
>> But we have to carry this all the way
back.
>> That's true.
>> It's lowkey kind of heavy.
>> Maybe we'll get a grab then.
>> Okay, so we got our drinking water
there. I think we'll probably have to
take a taxi back since that's going to
be really heavy. It shouldn't be too
much. No.
>> Picari sweat. Where is Picari sweat
from?
>> Japan.
>> Oh, is it?
>> Yeah.
>> First time I saw it, I saw it in Korea,
so I thought it was Korean. Soda should
be around here somewhere.
>> Yeah, right here.
>> But uh yeah, I guess cans are all right.
Or do you want like those small bottles?
You could buy like a big thing of soda,
a liter and a half, but I don't think
we'll drink this much soda in one
sitting. So, I think the cans would be
better to buy.
>> That's the only packet. Everything else
is individual. Oh, they got more packets
up here, but it's the same. Yeah, those
comes in packets of four.
>> Oh,
>> I guess let's get those. Or
>> what about up there?
>> Yeah, they have more sodas on the top
shelf. And there are many shelves here.
And all these shelves are filled with
sodas.
>> Carbonated yogurt drink like that. Uh
>> Milkus. Okay, let's uh just get this
then. Zero sugar. How many?
>> I probably won't drink that. You can
have them.
>> Okay, so we just grabbed the soda. We
got eight cans here. Yeah, that should
be good in terms of soda. Should we grab
a big one? is how much how many liters.
Okay, so we're just going to grab these
instead. The large bottles. We'll grab
two. They don't have zero sugar though,
but And then we can grab an A&W. So
there we got three soda. So we can check
that off the list. I think the detergent
will be there. It's on this aisle here.
>> Okay. So I think we're going to get a
liquid detergent since we don't see any
pods. So we're going to get this liquid
detergent for our washing machine. I
think all we need is one of these bags.
We don't need a solid container.
>> Yeah, this will work for us.
>> Okay, perfect. There is also powder.
Washing powder. Powder. But uh sometimes
powder leaves stains on your clothes, so
that's why I prefer to use liquid. We
can check that off the list. Detergent.
Okay, guys. We finished doing all our
shopping. We got a 12-pack of water, but
each bottle is 1 and 1/2 L. We also got
three bottles of soda. I got toothpaste
cuz I need it. And uh we also got
laundry detergent and some eggs and some
bananas. So, we managed to get almost
everything. What's the two things we
couldn't get?
>> Well, they did have toilet paper, but we
don't need a 12-pack. That's way too
much toilet paper per month.
>> Yeah, we need like half of that. We just
need six.
>> Maybe a six-pack. Uh and then we also
need a bar of soap. I don't know why
they didn't sell it here, but we'll go
to Watson's for that.
>> Yeah, we need a bar of soap. I like
using a bar of soap to either wash my
hands or to lather up my hands to wash
my body or to lather up my washcloth. So
yeah, this is all the stuff we bought.
And now we're waiting for our taxi.
Yeah, we booked a Grab and now we're
just waiting for it to come. It's 5
minutes away now. So he should be here
soon and then he'll bring us to where
we're staying. Normally we could just
walk back, but this is way too heavy to
carry for over a kilometer. I mean, we
could probably do it, but it's just more
convenient to just get a taxi. We're in
the elevator. I got the shopping. Leon
has the eggs and water. I kind of
started unpacking the stuff already. But
yeah, we got the toothpaste, bunch of
water. We put the eggs here. And I
already put the soda in the fridge just
because uh I didn't want it out. But
these bags feel like Feel that. Tell me
that does not feel different.
>> Yeah, I know. These aren't like regular
shopping bags, but these are recycled.
That's why.
>> Recycled.
>> They're 100% recycled. This is why they
feel like this. They're 100%
compostable. here. Wow.
>> Oh, I'm not a plastic bag. I'm 100%
compostable. This is biodegradable. So,
you can leave this and eventually it'll
just, you know, degrade compared to
plastic which like never decomposes. So,
if you just leave this, it'll decompose
eventually. But regular plastic wouldn't
decompose. It would uh stay as plastic
for, I don't know, thousand years.
>> Wow.
>> However long plastic lasts. That's why
it feels so different cuz I I was like,
this feels really different. It doesn't
feel like plastic.
>> Yeah. And I guess that's why
>> I think they're more environmentally
conscious in Malaysia cuz even the
straws and stuff, they're still on the
paper straws everywhere you go. And now
the fully compostable bags.
>> Yeah, that's cool. Guess we'll just
throw these away. I don't really know if
we have any use for them, but uh yeah,
besides that, we just have a bunch of
water. Let's just uh put this in the
fridge. Eh,
>> yeah, might as well.
>> So Leon just tore open this water bottle
plastic here, and now he's putting them
in the fridge. all the water bottles.
So, we got a lot of water here. How long
do you think this will last?
>> Uh I mean, I usually drink one a day.
So,
>> okay, we'll divide it in half and then
if these are up, you're going to have to
go and fill these up cuz we do have a
area to fill up the water bottles up a
couple floors. So, we don't necessarily
need to go buy more. We can just go
upstairs and refill these.
>> Imagine if these waters tasted like Dani
cuz we haven't tried this one yet.
Yeah, that would suck. But honestly, as
long as water's cold, it's not that bad.
So, now I'm going to pass this bottle to
Leon. I'll pass this one to Leon as
well.
And then the last two.
There you go. Throw that away. We'll
throw that out later. This is where we
put our shoes. The shoes aren't really
organized, but it's not that messy
either. But yeah, this is our apartment.
That's my room over there. Leon's room
is over there. Leon's washroom's here.
And my washroom is inside the room. This
right here is our living room. We have a
TV and this is our dining table. So,
this is where we'll eat. And this is our
kitchen area where we will be doing a
lot of cooking. Eh, so much. Oh, we
didn't buy oil or butter for the eggs.
>> Oh, that's right. I don't even know what
kind of pans and stuff we have here.
>> I guess we'll just have to boil the
eggs.
>> That's fine, too.
>> And eat boiled eggs.
>> Do we even have salt and pepper?
>> No idea. Oh, but we have a lot of
utensils here. So, okay guys, so Leon
asked me if this water tastes like Dani.
This water brand is Desa, but uh there
is a water brand in North America called
Dani, which is the worst water ever.
It's owned by uh the Coca-Cola company,
but Dani, no one buys that. Recently
there was a there was a big snowstorm
that went through America and I saw
videos on Tik Tok of like grocery stores
completely empty because people were
stocking up on different products and
different uh essentials so that they
could wait out the snowstorm without
worrying about supplies. And then they
were showing the water section and the
only water brand that no one bought was
Dani. The whole aisle was cleared. There
were no other water brands on the water
aisle because everyone bought them all.
All the other brands were sold out at
this particular grocery store. The only
brand that was still full was Dani. That
just shows you how much people hate
Dani. They really do not like the taste
of Dani. And I agree. Dani tastes like
chlorinated water. It tastes terrible.
It tastes like you took a bottle and you
went to your pool and you filled it up
with water and then you just started
drinking that and all of a sudden this
video is turning into like me roasting
Dani. But I'm just telling you guys the
facts. Dani does not taste good in North
America. But here we had Dani in
Malaysia and it wasn't that bad
actually. It tasted completely different
than the Dani in North America obviously
because they have different bottling
facilities. So, the water doesn't come
from the same place. That's why it
probably tastes different. Anyways, I
tried this water. Let me try it again
for you guys.
It's actually not bad. It kind of has
like a little little bit of sweetness to
it, but besides that, it tastes great
and it's warm. Usually, warm water
doesn't taste as good, but this water
tastes perfectly fine. Nothing wrong
with it. But yeah, I just wanted to give
you guys that history and little bit of
uh information on Dani. The other thing
I noticed is that these bananas, this
bunch of bananas look completely
different than the bananas that we get
in North America. In Canada and the
United States, we only get Cavendish
bananas. I believe they are called
Caendish bananas. Yo, Leon, what are the
bananas we get in Canada called?
Cavendish bananas, eh?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, they are called
Cavendish bananas. These ones are
definitely not Caendish bananas. I am
not sure what these bananas are called,
but uh let's try them. I do love love
love bananas. Truly, bananas are one of
my favorite fruit. I love bananas. They
just have like this creaminess to them
that really makes it like enjoyable to
eat. And they especially go well in
smoothies. I love putting a banana, just
one, in my uh fruit smoothie, and it
makes it like a lot thicker and
creamier. Now, let's uh try the banana.
I feel like the Cavendish banana is
sweeter and creamier.
>> That's not a Cavendish.
>> Does this look like a Cavendish to you,
>> dude? Like 99% of the bananas that are
sold
>> No.
>> in supermarkets are Cavendish? Yeah.
This is a show
>> in North America.
>> No, in the world. No, I guarantee you
that no Cavendish will have a bottom
like this.
>> You know, I'm not a banana expert, so I
could be wrong, but if I was a betting
man, I would not bet that this is a
Cavendish banana. Let me take a picture.
There are literally hundreds, if not
thousands of species of uh bananas. So,
I highly doubt that these are Cavendish.
>> I know, but like I think the stat is
like crazy. It's like 99.9% are
Cavendish. And the only place you can
really buy other species is like local
markets or you grow it yourself.
>> I don't know. here. I imagine they have
a lot of banana production here. I don't
think it's a Caven dish. I could be
wrong, but it's not bad. It's not bad.
It's not as sweet and as creamy
>> as they are in Canada.
>> It's called a baby banana.
>> A baby banana
>> or lady finger banana.
>> See guys, what did I tell you?
>> It's a variation of a caven dish,
>> but it's not.
>> Oh, in Malaysia it's called the pisang
mas. Yeah, I was telling them about Dani
and how no one in North America drinks
Dani. Or if they do, it's cuz they have
to.
>> Yeah, it's not good stuff.
>> It's not. And I forgot to mention, we
also bought this laundry detergent. This
is liquid laundry detergent. You can
also get uh pods, laundry pods or
powder. It comes in powder form as well.
I prefer pods. Those are the easiest cuz
you just grab one pod and you throw it
in with your clothes and you don't
worry. This one you got to like pour it
in. Sometimes measure it out. So it's
like one more step, but it's really not
a big deal. But yeah, we got this as
well.
>> Are you going to wash some clothes?
>> I have a lot of laundry from Paneang
that I need to wash. So,
>> but how are you going to dry it? Cuz we
don't have a dryer.
>> That's a washer and dryer.
>> Oh,
>> but I will wash it there, but I'll air
dry it outside. Let me just show you our
view. I am going to maybe do a full tour
of our apartment. If you guys want to
see that, let me know in the comments if
you want to see that. But for now, I'll
just show you our beautiful view. First,
let me put this filter on because it
will be too bright. Okay, so I'm going
to open the door to our balcony and I'll
show you the view here. Look at that
view.
Over there, we could see the five main
towers of Koala Lumpur. There you have
arguably the most famous of them all,
the Patronus Twin Towers. There is
another one right there. I'm not sure
the name. And there's another one right
there, which is one of the tallest
buildings in the world. So, yeah, that's
our view. Let me know what you guys
think. I said in a previous video that I
really want to have a balcony with a
nice view, and uh that's why we decided
to rent this place for the month because
it has a nice view. Let me know guys,
what do you think of the POV? Because
for the POV,
I use this camera and I mount it onto my
chest. So then you guys can see my POV.
So this is essentially what I'm looking
at. So let me know, do you guys want to
see more videos with that camera from my
POV and then explaining stuff in English
using comprehensible input and also
talking clearly and slowly. If you want
more videos like that, let me know in
the comments. If not, then I'll stick to
using this camera and uh it'll be like
this. More like Leon holding the camera
or me holding the camera and talking
like this. Or do you like the POV? The
whole video doesn't have to be POV, but
maybe portions like the grocery store or
doing something else can be POV cuz
sometimes it's easier to go film with
that small camera. Let me know if you
guys liked it or not and I'll see you
guys in the next video. If you're
serious about becoming fluent in
English, I've built a full speaking,
shadowing, and pronunciation course you
can follow step by step. You get instant
access to over 60 video lessons right
away. And I add three to five brand new
lessons every week to keep the content
fresh. And you're not just getting
videos. You also get an exclusive Chat
GPT prompt to help you master the
pronunciation of any word. plus a
step-by-step structure to follow so you
know exactly how to practice and get the
most out of every lesson. Inside, we
train pronunciation, accent, rhythm, and
natural speaking so you stop hesitating
and start speaking with real confidence.
Now, here's a sneak peek at what you get
the moment you join. So I wouldn't take
legal a came down to heat already so
cranky. The jeans and one hoodie which I
clicked the link in my description to
join. So this is our list. Toilet paper.
>> The biggest citrus fruit you can buy.
>> When's the last time you even had any
bananas? And I'm going to place it into
my shopping cart.
>> You got to remember the skin is thick.
>> Yeah. I won't be doing any cooking, but
let's add banana to the list. Are a
bunch of fish here.
>> This almost looks like a piranha.
>> They'll scan this barcode and I Oh,
eggs. You think we should buy some eggs?
Here we have packaged goods and there
are many shelves here and we're going to
get a liquid detergent since
>> they're 100% compostable here.
>> So Leon just tore open this plastic
water bottle.
>> I don't even know what kind of pans and
stuff we have here.
>> I guess because people were stocking up
on different they really do not like the
taste of the sonnie and I agree. So they
are called cabin dish bananas. These
ones I forgot to mention, we also bought
this laundry cuz it has a nice view. And
if you want to get these t-shirts, check
out voca English.com. And remember guys,
you will become fluent in