I don't like being spoken to in a
disrespectful way. Um, but I do feel
that whatever is happening is making you
upset or sad and I'd like to talk about
it. Can we do that?
Now, what I just said was two things.
The first one is I don't like being
spoke to in disrespect, which means I
will end this conversation if you
continue this way. That's called drawing
a boundary. I'm saying don't talk to me
this way. That is a boundary. You talk
to me this way, the conversation's over.
But there is an element of kindness
because I'm respecting the fact that
you're human and you're upset about
something and I want to work with you to
make you feel better. So even though I'm
saying this is a boundary, I'm saying as
long as you respect my boundary and
don't speak to me in that way, I will
help you or try to help you feel better
or try and make this work. Okay? So
that's the first one. So it talks about
respect, respect for the other person
and respect for yourself. You're asking
them to respect you and you will respect
them and help resolve the problem or
situation. Okay? And this is, you know,
can be used almost any time and it
should be the first line of defense
talking about respect for each other,