We're against Ricky 5,600 MMR. I'm
playing random uh random human on my
main account here. Um and he is also
random from the looks of it. Yeah. So,
it's random against random. So, very
difficult to know uh what you're going
to be facing. Of course, there are how
many permutations are there? 16, right?
16 possible scenarios. Four mirror
matchups.
So, we're just going to make a generic
walloff build
>> and start with uh
>> a good first hero. Arc major mounting.
If we want to be really
surprising, I can go for a mounting.
>> Very difficult hero to make work on this
map. Actually,
>> though I can think of one particular way
where it can work quite well. I could
pull this camp and storm bolts around
it.
>> I would need an arcane vault to fall
back to to heal up.
>> Could secure a big item that way.
Probably best if I first
find him somewhere wherever he is.
Stormbbolt him to remove his town portal
so that I can control his location a
little bit more
>> and then try to see if I can use it to
creep the overglord. Yeah, I'll go
mounting first. footman scout to see
what race he is so I can start drawing a
decision matrix for where he's going to
be
>> with creeping
>> requ
7 seconds we'll pull militia in Easy.
Off I go then.
>> Ready and waiting. It's hammer time.
>> Piercing damage tanked by the mount
king. Normal damage by the militia.
>> Let's do this.
>> Kill one by one unit to lower his damage
output.
>> He is undead. On my way.
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
you? I'm ready for
>> He's not creeping the expected camp.
>> Is he taking the small green camp or
immediately fast expanding? It is a
small green camp. It is cry lord first
on my way. Let's get the word.
I'm right.
>> Nice try, but that actually cost him a
lot of time. OR LUMBER
on my way.
>> Kind of slow for human.
>> You're kind of slow.
>> Of course. LET'S GET
>> ATTACKING ORDERS. That's more like it.
>> TAKE THIS, YOU SAY.
>> OH, he's getting it.
>> It's hammer.
>> FORCES ARE UNDER ATTACK.
>> WHAT'S HAPPENING? Let's get it on.
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
LET'S DO THIS. Let's get moving. Say,
you're kind of slow. YOU
>> I'M ready and waiting.
>> We have to go again immediately because
he's going to expand.
>> All right.
>> What's happening?
>> Let's get moving. You're kind of
>> I need to get staff and telly so that I
can't get surrounded and killed. That
was a nice surround by him.
>> On my way. Right. Ready for my
>> Let's get moving.
>> SAY THE WORD. RIGHT. LET ME ADAM. I lord
of course
>> I'm ready and will take you down.
>> We'll get boots first.
>> On my way. On my way.
>> He's not getting a lot of resources by
the way.
>> He's not gathering a whole lot of
lumber.
>> Say the word.
>> I need stop of telly cuz he's level two
already.
>> Say the word. What do you need?
>> Under attack.
>> Let's get it on.
>> WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> LET'S GET MOVING.
>> YES, my lord.
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
you?
>> Say the word.
>> I'm ready and waiting. Orders.
>> I'm ready and waiting. It's hammer time.
You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
you?
>> You need the word.
>> Are slow for a human, aren't you?
>> It's hammer time.
>> If he gets a vanilla surround on me,
>> get moving.
It's really bad
>> because then I can't staff oft then he
uses impale for the
>> what's happening.
>> Say the word
under attack.
>> Let's get moving.
>> Say the word. I'm ready and waiting.
>> Take this you bastard. Let's get it on
>> for the interrupt.
>> What's happening?
>> That's more like it. Let's get it on.
It's hammer.
>> Okay, good.
That's more like it is. You're kind of
slow for a human, aren't you?
>> I'm ready.
>> Blood mage second.
Forces are under attack.
>> Human, aren't you?
>> What do you need?
>> What's happening? Let's do this.
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
you?
>> What do you need?
>> Say the word.
>> Finally, he has Narubian in his main.
>> Let's do this.
>> All right.
>> What's happening?
>> Yes, my say the word. Let's get moving.
>> Can I still cancel his gold mine?
>> Let's get moving.
>> I think so. You're kind.
>> It would be very big if I can cancel it
once.
>> He's got to try and body block me.
>> What's happening?
>> Let's get moving.
>> Let's get it on.
>> What do you need?
>> You're kind of slow for a human.
>> What's happening?
>> You need
What's happening
under attack?
>> Oh, this is big.
>> Huge.
>> Let's get moving.
>> We should move soon. I sense some kind
of human.
>> Now we do this.
>> What is it?
>> I'm ready. What's the hold up?
>> I feel edgy.
>> Let's get moving.
>> I sense
>> what's happening.
>> Elusive.
>> Let's get moving. What's happening?
>> We'll do one priest and a sorceress.
>> We should move.
>> Kind of slow for a human, aren't you?
>> That's more like it. Let's do this.
And then we bring uh
>> we bring militia to make a workshop
offensive mangan.
>> Let's open this up so I can defend
against beles.
of human.
>> That's more like
>> my people.
>> Of course.
>> My word.
>> Let's get
my
>> On my way.
What's the hole?
>> Off I go then.
>> Kill my own
>> footage.
I go then.
>> All right.
>> What's happening? Let's get moving.
What's happening?
>> Let's level up for King. Our forces are
under attack.
>> He's still tier.
one.
>> I think we'll get flame strike
>> if you want. I guess I can
>> work.
What's happening?
>> That's more like
Let's get moving. Let's get it on. Let's
do this.
Okay,
>> let's do this.
>> What is it?
>> What do you need? What's happening?
>> I think I must be
>> I said something.
>> My forces are under attack.
>> I feel edgy.
Do you requ
>> right away?
>> Let's get moving.
>> What's happening?
>> It's hammer time.
>> More forces are under attack.
>> Is someone here?
>> My miss rally.
>> You should move, sir.
>> Let's get moving.
>> Help me. I'm ready.
>> You're kind of slow for human action.
>> Let's get it.
>> Let's get it on. What the
cleans,
you won't get me, Lord.
>> Not enough.
>> Do you require me?
>> Let's get That's more like it. That's
more like it.
>> Help me. I think it must be abandoned.
>> Our forces are under attack.
>> IT'S MY
EYES. Let's get to the target.
>> GG.
>> Nice. Good game.
Micro wars. That guy was pretty good.
So, you're going to be watching the
video guides that I shared with you,
Papa Asher. So, I don't have to ne
necessarily build up this what I'm doing
now in the exact same way. You'll watch
it later and you'll put things in
context, but in it, I'm going to be
talking about a lot of different things.
Obviously, uh you are not completely new
to Warcraft 3, but it's good to know the
following. Everyone has the same income
in Warcraft 3. The income caps at five
beons in gold and you'll make eight
workers on wood and that's about it and
you generally don't touch your income
anymore. The next forms of income are
through upkeep
in the form of a restriction. So if you
get big army, you get little money
basically. So big armies need to fight
or gain advantage or kill or survive.
Small armies need to dodge, scout,
evade, be tactical, hit and run, and
build up capital. So, if you're ready to
become dangerous, go over 50 and use it.
And if you're ready to be economical,
stay under 50 and use it. That's how you
manage an economy in Warcraft 3, because
five in gold is the max. Eight on wood
is generally enough for a human.
I'm playing against a greedy player. Uh
there's another way to gain gold, which
is to creep, of course. Creeping is
where you kill neutral camps on the map.
Kill them for experience points. A gold
kill bounty and items. Items can either
be used or sold. Selling items gives you
gold. Using them makes you stronger
without increasing your upkeep.
he was listening to. Uh so uh as a new
player, we are going to be keeping our
base open because the chance that we
stuck ourselves in base is too great. So
a pro player would build their farm
here, wall off and then make sure they
never get stuck. But new players will
get stuck and there will be no one to
get them out of the washing machine. So
we're going to keep a hole here so we
can easily get out and we won't need to
call on any step siblings. We're going
to make arc mage and when the barracks
finishes, we're going to be making
footmen from that.
Generally, we want to make about three
to five footmen and then transition to
rifles and priests.
>> Job done.
>> Uh,
okay. Sorry, it's really hard to have
two conversations and play at the same
time, so I can usually not respond much
to my opponent. Uh we're going to be
taking some creep camps. Uh every creep
camp has its own approach. You'll see
that the sixth guide in my series on
followgrubby.com will go extensively
into creeping AI manipulation. This is
actually a really important part of the
game. So if you look at this camp,
there's a no warden. He has a mana bar.
That generally means he needs to die
first. Also, it's a knowledge issue.
Sometimes some creeps, you need to
handle them differently than others. So
this guy will actually purge whatever
melee unit or summon comes into his
range. So we first land a hit on him
>> with footman so that he gets purged.
Then we summon water elemental. If we
make the water elemental and walk into
the camp, he will purge the alley and we
will lose health on the alley. It will
then be less healthy and that's going to
cost us
creeping efficiency. Creeping efficiency
is all about doing it fast and taking
little damage.
>> So I'm going to summon second water
elemental. Kill the two ranged first
because they are like glass cannon.
Ranged have high damage and low health.
>> If arch mage gets attacked, we just walk
away.
>> We put some units on the ark mage and we
keep creeping with the rest.
always put some units
>> ready for action.
>> Town is under
>> Don't let him last hit.
>> What is it now?
>> Forces are under attack.
>> You require my assistance.
>> Yes, my
word.
>> Get on.
>> Good battle.
Okay, don't forget to tech up while
you're getting harassed.
>> What is it now?
>> Uh, anytime Ark Mage comes after you,
just run into your base, summon militia,
attack the wolves with everything, and
put about two to three footmen on his
farces are under attack.
>> And that way he takes damage.
>> Okay, we're at 30 population. Tech has
started. We're going to make a
blacksmith to transition to rifles. Now
I know you were asking meord
of course right
>> I know you were asking me about uh
should I expand should I not expand it
seem I always seem to be doing the wrong
thing just don't expand uh in the
beginning
>> if you don't know uh properly how to
build like win conditions yet uh expand
is one win condition
>> but there's many other win conditions
that are easier to play
>> get on with it
>> uh never build blacksmith arcane vault
or lumber lumberm mill before you tech
to tier two. It is very important to get
your tech started early so that you can
make your mounting king and start
leveling him. My goal for newbies is
that you
>> get level three on your first hero.
That's one of your goals and level three
on your second hero. That's your
secondary goal. And then to get 60
population and fight.
>> That's my goals for you. So, um, yeah,
we can't get level three on theord
on the second hero if we don't have one.
>> I think that should be clear.
>> What is it now?
>> Whatever.
Get on the
>> So, it's okay to make a vault now
because tier 2 has started. We're going
to make another farm and we're going to
start making some riflemen. units get
hurt, I click the unit usually, and then
I press backspace. So, I click the unit,
press backspace, which goes to the town
center, the town hall, and then I put
the unit there, and I make sure it's not
in my control group anymore.
>> So, we're level three now. That's the
number one goal that I ask people to
get. Level three, first hero. Usually, I
I recommend people to dare to get
aggressive once you get your first hero,
level three. Tier two finishes arcane
sanctum mount king build the sanctum
with two peasants and at the same time
get the long rifle upgrade.
>> Uh why is it so important to go get
aggressive immediately when you get uh
level three? It's because the power
spike imbalance is the greatest
>> the earlier you bring it because the
amount of time between me being level
three and him
>> is the greatest the earlier I go
>> say the word
>> and how you use it well you can harass
peons burrows units
every time footman drop low click it
Press backspace and then take the rest
of your army. Control one so it's not in
your group.
>> Mountain king comes out. We take
militia,
>> send it to the expansion
>> and take a regen scroll and then go
there. This is how mount King gets level
two.
>> Now we don't see any units that can
ensnare me yet.
are under attack.
>> So, we can actually harass him a bit
more. But he did a surround. Not bad.
>> So, how do we get our second hero level
three as fast as possible? By not having
our arc mage there when we're farming.
>> Even if he was there, I would walk out
of range
>> over
>> so that he doesn't share the XP.
You're kind of human.
>> One cool thing that you can do to make
creeping faster
>> is uh to lose your arc mage to a slow
>> and the creeps focusing you.
>> That's really great.
>> So again, if possible, we kill the
creeps when arch mage is not there so
that mountain can get solo XP.
Send the peasants home.
>> Remember my my goal for you is 3 360
level three hero level three hero and 60
population.
>> You're kind of slow.
>> So we're not there yet. And when you do
that, you should also have one heal
scroll and one invoke.
>> Let's get moving. More gold.
>> Yes, my
>> right away.
>> In on your front line and heal scroll on
>> anyone.
>> Usually arc mage cuz he's in a better
position to share.
>> So, we just need one more camp to get
level up. We use crystal ball to see
what are you doing. Tier three. Are you
expanding here? Are you expanding here?
No. So, he has no wink con because he
has no tech and no money.
>> GET ON WITH IT.
LET'S do this.
>> Let's get it.
>> What is it now?
>> Well,
okay. Now we're level three.
>> So remember the rule is 33 60.
>> Is someone injured? What hails you?
>> Yes, my friend.
>> And even though we're not 60 yet, if you
are ahead with 50, you can start
pressuring and then prepare to go over.
>> If you're not ahead yet, you can still
posture aggressively because we now have
two power spikes.
>> Level three hero, level three hero.
Those are two power spikes. And going 60
pop is the next power spike. What is it?
>> Is someone
>> Let's do this.
>> Here we can get another heal scroll,
which is another which is a substitute
for going over 50 cuz if I didn't buy
it, I could go over 50 right now.
>> Of course, I can even go over 50 with a
single unit. I usually like to go with
more, but it's okay to go with a single.
>> So, we're on the way to 60 now. We
getting less income, but we have level
33. So, we're basically combining three
power spikes at the same time for the
win condition of killing him.
Win conditions come in the form of bonus
gold through having an expansion,
>> killing someone with a big army or
better heroes
>> or going to a high unit tech.
>> So, you could go Torrance or Chimera.
Those are all win conditions.
Let's do this. Let's get it on.
>> And then with this, you can build a
shop.
Building a shop allows us to replenish
and keep producing units when you're
attacking.
>> And now we can get like clarity regen
for the mountain king.
>> Let's get it all.
I am your servant.
>> And then you can make towers as well.
>> By the power of the light.
>> GG.
I'm accidentally shouting.
Why not put some speed on me hero? Uh,
you can and and you should. It's good.
Why are you yelling? Uh, I learned using
caps lock in Age of Empires 2 and 4, and
I am pressing it by accident now because
of latent muscle memory of playing those
games, even though I don't have anything
bound to it in Warcraft 3. I'm just
randomly pressing caps and having
trouble controlling the volume of my
voice.