Most people read books to get smarter.
They get more informed, but their life
stays exactly the same. But a few books
make you dangerously smart. They rewire
your brain and change how you think, how
you decide, and how you see what others
don't. I've been a CEO and board adviser
to billion-dollar companies. And I've
distilled hundreds of titles down to
four that function as a toolkit for a
self-taught genius. But first, something
more valuable than the list itself, a
framework for finding the books that
actually rewire you. Every book is an
investment of time and attention. Most
of them entertain you, some inform you,
but a very few change you. Here's how to
tell the difference. Before you commit
to a book, ask three questions. I call
them the three gates. Gate number one,
the operator. Will this book change how
you think or just change what you think?
If a book can install new mental moves,
new ways to see, to reason, to decide,
then it'll make you a better operator
because it will bring the kind of system
upgrade that we're talking about here.
Gate number two, the challenger. Does
this book make you uncomfortable? Does
it challenge your beliefs? You know, the
best books don't confirm what you know.
They dismantle everything you're certain
about page by page permanently. If you
finish a book and you feel validated,
you've learned nothing new. And gate
number three, the fire alarm. I always
ask myself, will this book stop me from
doing dumb things with confidence? Will
it prevent an expensive mistake? Great
books hand you tools that stop you from
confusing confidence from competence. If
a book passes any of these three gates,
it will upgrade your inner operating
system. Now, of course, I love books
like Grit or Atomic Habits or So Good
They Can't Ignore You. Great books.
They're brilliant for building tactics
and changing your daily behavior. We
want to go beyond just behavioral
shifts. We want to upgrade and scale our
entire way of thinking. Most books will
change your speed. These four will
change your engine. Book number one was
a gut punch to me. It forced me to ask a
terrifying question. Are my heroes
visionaries or just lottery winners?
Nasim Talib talks about it in our first
book, Fooled by Randomness. He shows why
randomness manufactures geniuses and it
changes the way we think about outcomes.
Look at the math. Imagine you invite
10,000 traders from Wall Street to a
stadium once a year. They flip a coin,
heads, they double their money. Tails,
they go bust. They go home. After 1
year, half of them will go home. 5,000
will come back. If you keep doing this
for 5 years, then 5 years later, 312 of
those traders will be left in the
stadium. They won all five times. Now,
these 312 people will be on the cover of
Forbes. They'll write books. They'll
sell you systems. They'll start a
YouTube channel. But are they masters?
No. They are a statistical certainty.
They didn't beat the system. They were
produced by the system. That's why
Talup's point is chilling. You cannot
distinguish a master from a lucky idiot
simply by looking at their track record.
At the AI company where I was CEO, we
were one of the fastest growing firms in
the US. I was surrounded by some of the
smartest minds, exceptional talent, but
we also got a once in a decade tailwind
we didn't control. The internet was
overwhelmed at that moment with the
cyber threat of fake transactions and
bots that acted like humans. It had
become an existential crisis for the
internet. So, we were the right company
at the right time. Was our team
exceptional? Sure. Did we work our butts
off? Of course. But without that
existential threat, without that
tailwind, all of my visionary strategies
would have been a forgotten footnote
somewhere. Because we often confuse a
tailwind with our own talent. This is
called the survivorship bias. Stop
trying to be a better forecaster of your
future. Start trying to be less fragile,
more resilient to randomness. Now, what
if you've read this book already? Then
the graduate level upgrade would be a
book from a Nobel Prize winner, Daniel
Conaman, Thinking Fast and Slow. Conaman
shows you exactly what's happening in
your brain when you were being fooled by
randomness. His book shows the exact
wiring. System one that makes you jump
to conclusions immediately and system
two which helps us avoid those mistakes.
How do you make all of this actionable?
Here are two steps. First, the luck
labor audit. Every Friday, audit your
wins into two columns. Column A, labor.
What did I control? And column B, luck,
timing, tailwinds. If column B is empty,
then your ego is ruining all the driving
and you are headed for a crash. Second,
the wreckage tour. Now, this is my
favorite. Stop studying just the
survivors. Find the people who made your
exact bet and didn't make it. Learn from
them. Because if your plan only works in
the commies, it's not a plan. It's a
prayer. Book number two is about the
biggest mistake successful people make.
When you win, you stop searching and you
somehow start defending what you already
know. Adam Grant calls this out in his
book, Think Again. This is our second
book. The smarter you are, the harder it
is to change your mind. There was a
study done on tax professionals.
Researchers gave complex tax code and
problems to both junior students and
seasoned CPAs. When the rules changed
just a little, the experts failed three
times more often than the students
because the experts were so certain. The
more you know, the less you see. I call
it the proficiency prison. And the case
studies are everywhere. Kodak invented
digital photography. They had the
technology. They had the talent. They
had the resources. But they buried it.
Why? Because it threatened their film
business. And Kodak's no more.
Blockbuster had a chance to buy Netflix
for $50 million and they passed. Now,
none of these executives were stupid.
They were just trying to protect
yesterday's wins. They were trapped in
their own proficiency prison. We wear
three masks when we don't want to change
our thinking. the preacher, the
prosecutor, and the politician. The
preacher defends the belief like it's a
scripture. Prosecutors will defend their
belief by spotting flaws in others. And
politicians, well, they will say
whatever the room wants to hear. Now,
what do you do to take these masks off?
Be a scientist. Treat your beliefs as
hypothesis. Run experiments. Update your
beliefs based on data. Now, if you've
read this book, then the graduate level
work is Innovator's Dilemma by Clayton
Christensen. That book shows you exactly
why companies love to stay in their
proficiency prison. Intel dominated the
computer chip market for decades. They
were so busy protecting that business,
they completely ignored the GPU
revolution. Today, Intel is roughly a
$220 billion giant. But Nvidia is a $4
trillion ecosystem. And that is what the
innovator's dilemma is all about. The
action plan here, there are three
mindsets that help me a lot. scientist,
stranger, startup. First, the scientist
mode. Take your strongest current belief
and rewrite it as I currently believe X.
But it could be wrong if XYZ it turns on
the scientist mode on demand. Second,
the stranger mode. Try to explain your
strategy or plan to someone outside of
your industry, someone who doesn't know
anything about it. Where they get
confused is exactly where you need to
focus. And finally, the startup mode. I
never hire a seale executive in any
company that I work with until I ask
them this very question. If you had a
million dollars and all the technology
in the world, what would you build to
take down your own company? If they can
map out their own destruction, they're
scientists. If they defend the status
quo, they are just priests. The
scientist is never certain and the
priest is never curious. The third book
completely changes how you judge your
own decisions. Annie Duke spent 20 years
being a world-class poker player. In her
book, Thinking in Bets, she talks about
this interesting way of thinking. Treat
every decision like a bet. When I was
coming to Boston from Mumbai for my
master's study, the university had only
given me a conditional scholarship
because my scores were okay. They
weren't great. So they said, you know,
pay for the first semester yourself and
teach undergrad mathematics at the same
time. And the department said, you know,
if you survive, we'll pay for the rest
of the graduate program, and if not, you
have to pay out of pocket. And I said,
sure. What they didn't know was that if
I failed, I had no way to pay for the
rest of the program. I thought in terms
of bets. I outlined my strengths, my
weaknesses. I made a list of things that
could go wrong, and I calculated my
odds. There was about a 30% chance that
I would fail. I was okay taking that
risk. I bought a one-way ticket from
Mumbai to Boston. It wasn't bravery. I
really didn't have a plan B. The only
plan was to focus on increasing my odds
every day. Now, of course, the bet could
have gone the other way. But the point
is to know exactly what is at risk and
whether you have a plan to manage that
risk. And if you've read this book
already, the graduate version is super
forecasting. Philip Tetllock studied
25,000 predictions over decades and
found that the most accurate people on
Earth or the super forecasters don't
think in terms of yes or no. They think
in terms of bets, odds, possibilities,
probabilities, and they update that
number every time new data hits the
wire. They aren't trying to be right all
the time. All they're trying to do is to
be less wrong after every iteration. So,
how do you put this in action? The
simplest one is to decision journal.
Just do it for 30 days. I did it. Super
helpful. For the next 30 days, for
example, before any major decision or a
pivot, write down three things. One,
your confidence level, 0 to 100%. Number
two, what you know, what you don't, and
what evidence will change your odds. And
number three, write down three reasons
why you could be wrong about this
decision. And track that for 30 days.
Your emotions will get quieter. Your
thinking will get clearer. When you
start thinking in bets, you stop
reacting and you start revising. Book
number four is the most dangerous one on
this list. Everything we have covered so
far leads to this single question. What
if your intelligence itself is the trap?
David Robson spent years studying the
relationship between intelligence and
cognitive failure. And the book he wrote
was the intelligence trap. He shows that
smart people have this special failure
mode because they can rationalize
anything and they become their own
enemies because they become their own
defense attorneys. Most people hit a
wall and question themselves. Smart
people hit a wall and question the wall.
And I've learned this the hard way. At
my first job after coming out of MIT, I
was the head of marketing for a global
company. And in hindsight, I did not
build an advisory board of mentors. And
I did not ask dumb questions early on.
And when the company hired a new
president, he could see that I wasn't
ready for a promotion. So he brought in
an SVP of marketing instead of promoting
me. And in hindsight, I think I had
trapped myself in my own narrative about
my capabilities, about my competence.
And that's a very subtle trap. The book
helps you avoid such self-justification.
The one drill that helps me the most is
what I call the anti-mentor. So before
any major decision, ask one person in
your life whose judgment you trust to
argue the opposite case as hard as they
can. Tell them don't be polite. Try to
kill the plan on paper. And if no one in
your life can do that, that's also a
great problem to solve. The second
practice is the empty cup. Before your
next highstakes meeting, write down
three naive questions you would be
embarrassed to ask and go ahead and ask.
Anyway, there is a concept in the Zen
Buddhism called Shosin, beginner's mind.
The expert's cup is always full, no room
for anything new. The beginner's cup is
always empty, ready to receive
everything. I saw this on a train ride
many years ago. I remember we were going
to New York City from New Jersey with
our two kids and they were little, seven
and four. The train has to go through
this tunnel because it goes under the
river and it was pitch dark outside and
both kids were so incredibly excited to
see it. They just started giggling with
joy. Pure shin, pure magic. And that
made me think. I took that train and
went through the same tunnel twice a
day. And never even once was I
overwhelmed with this feeling of sheer
joy. As we grow old, why do we treat our
sense of wonder as weakness and
embarrassment? Why treat our curiosity
as if it's a curse? These books will
help you reset your system so you can
answer those questions. But the ultimate
system upgrade isn't adding more to your
cup. It's your ability to go through
that dark tunnel and still find magic in
it.
If you like this video, don't forget to
subscribe and check out my most recent
video here. Thank you and I love you.